<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Policy xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <PolicyId>3</PolicyId>
  <PolicyName>CIS for SQL Server 2000</PolicyName>
  <PolicyDescription>Center for Internet Security - Benchmark for Microsoft SQL Server 2000, V 1.0, December, 2005</PolicyDescription>
  <IsSystemPolicy>false</IsSystemPolicy>
  <IsDynamic>true</IsDynamic>
  <DynamicSelection>Left(version,2) ='8.'</DynamicSelection>
  <InterviewName>CIS Interview Checks</InterviewName>
  <InterviewText>Benchmark for Microsoft SQL Server 2000 


Version 1.0 
December, 2005


1.1 Physical security Place the SQL Server in an area where it will be physically secure. 
Place the server where only authorized personnel can obtain access. 


1.3 SQL Servers accessed via Internet 
If the SQL Server is being accessed via the Internet, place the SQL Server inside a DMZ with the Web Server. 

1.4 SQL Servers accessed via Internet - Put a firewall between your server and the Internet. 
In a multi-tier environment, use multiple firewalls to create more secure screened subnets. Consider separating Web logic and business logic onto separate computers. 


1.5 IPSEC - Use IPSEC policy filters to block connections to ports other than the configured SQL Server ports. 
IPSEC offers authentication, integrity, confidentiality, and anti-replay services. SSL can provide these services for all database connections; however, IPSEC can allow these services to be configured on selected computers and ports. 

1.6 Encryption - Implement SSL. Use the fully-qualified DNS name of the server in the certificate to help prevent masquerading. 

1.7 Test and development servers - Maintain test and development servers on a separate network segment from the production servers. Test patches carefully before applying them to production systems. 

1.8 Dedicated Server - Install SQL Server on a computer that does not provide additional services, e.g., Web or Mail Services. Vulnerabilities in other application services could lead to a compromise of the SQL Server. 


1.9 OS Benchmark Configuration - Configure Windows 2000 Server Level II benchmark settings with the following modifications:



1.9.3 Disk subsystem - Use RAID for critical data files Raid Level 10 is recommended. Use the level of RAID which will provide the best reliability and performance for your environment. 
 
1.9.4 Separate partitions - Create separate partitions for OS/SQL program files, SQL data files, and SQL transaction logs. Separate partitions provide greater protections via host and file permissions at the volume level as well as allowing greater control over data storage usage and monitoring of the database. 

1.10 Services - Disable the following services on a SQL Server machine 
The disabling of services has to be balanced with application requirements, since certain applications require the use of certain services to function correctly. 
 

1.13 Local users group membership - Assign the local service account as a member of only the Users group The ‘Users’ group is a local machine group.

1.14 Domain users group membership Make a domain service account a member of only the Domain Users group 
 
1.15 SQL Server service account rights 
Grant the SQL Server service account(s) the following rights: 
These rights are assigned by default. 
Log on as a service, Act as part of the operating system, Log on as a batch job, Replace a process-level token, Bypass traverse checking, Adjust memory quotas for a process, Permission to start SQL Server, Active Directory, Helper, Permission to start SQL Writer

1.16 SQL Server Agent service account rights - Grant the SQL Server Agent service account(s) the following rights: 
These rights are assigned by default. 
Log on as a service,Act as part of the operating system Only on Windows 2000,Log on as a batch job,Replace a process-level token,Bypass traverse checking,Adjust memory quotas for a process

1.17 Integration Service account rights -
Grant the Integration Service account(s) the following 
rights: 
Log on as a service, Permission to write to the application event log,Bypass traverse checking,Create global objects,Impersonate a client after authentication


2.4 Naming conventions In naming SQL Server instances, limit the instance name to less than 16 characters with no reference to a version number or other sensitive information. 
Version or other sensitive information in the server name makes it easier for an attacker to develop an attack strategy against the server. 
 
2.5 SQL Server instances Keep an inventory of all versions, editions and languages of SQL Server. Include instances of SQLEXPRESS. SQL Scan and SQL Check are some of the tools that can be used to scan for instances of SQL Server within a domain. 

2.8 Registry editing tools Remove Registry editing tools from the SQL Server machine, if possible. Remove Regedit.exe from the server.


3.2.1 Auto Restart SQL Server - Set the SQL Server service start mode to ‘Automatic’ This is found in the SQL Server Configuration Manager. 
 
3.2.2 Auto Restart SQL Server Agent - If the SQL Server Agent is required, set the ‘SQL Server Agent’ start mode to ‘Automatic’. This is found in the SQL Server Configuration Manager. 

3.2.3 Distributed Transaction Coordinator - Set the ‘Distributed Transaction Coordinator’ service start mode to ‘Disabled’ if this service is not required. This is found in the SQL Server Configuration Manager. 

3.2.4 Cross database-ownership chaining - Disable the cross_db_ownership_chaining option. Use sp_dboption to check for databases for which cross-database ownership chaining is enabled. This is found in the General page of SQL Server Properties window. This is disabled by default. 




3.2.9 Backup/Restore from tape timeout - Set the Backup/Restore from tape timeout period to “Try for 5 minutes” This option is found in the Database Settings page of SQL Server Properties window. 


3.2.10 Media Retention - Set the default backup media retention to the minimum number of days needed to retain a full backup of the database. Ideally, this should be as high as your resources permit. 
This option is found in the Database Settings page of SQL Server Properties window. (Idera SQLsafe provides a media Retention Policy)

3.3 Data Directory The default data directory should be a dedicated data partition  

3.4 Data Directory The default log directory should be a dedicated partition separate from all programs and data

3.7 Other SQL Server - Configuration Options - Save a maximum of 14 SQL error logs . Truncate logs on a regular schedule, weekly, bi-weekly etc. to prevent oversize logs. This option is found under Management-&gt; SQL Server Logs -&gt;Configure


3.9 Trace Messages Error Log/Include execution trace messages = off General Page on SQL Server Agent properties


4.1 Permissions on OS tools - Restrict access to the executables in the System32 directory eg. Explorer.exe and cmd.exe. 
Remove the Users group’s permission (if any) to executables. Assign Administrators Full Control. 
 
4.2 SQL Server install directory permissions - Modify the permissions to the [Drive]:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server directory. 
Assign the SQL Server service account Full Control. Remove the Users group’s 

4.3 SQL Server database instance directory permissions Delete or secure old setup files. Protect files in the &lt;system drive&gt;:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server\MSSQL.X\MSSQL\Install, e.g., sqlstp.log, sqlsp.log and setup.iss. 
‘.X’ represents the installations of various SQL Server installs due to the fact that multiple instances of SQL Server or SQL Express can be installed. If the current system was upgraded from SQL Server version 2000, check setup.iss in the %Windir% folder and the sqlstp.log in the Windows Temp folder for passwords. Microsoft distributes a free utility called Killpwd, which will locate and remove passwords found in these setup files from your system. This tool does not work with a native SQL 2005 installation. Microsoft is scheduled to release an updated tool, but no release date has been given at this time. 

4.4 Assigning System Administrators role - When assigning database administrators to the System Administrators role, map their Windows accounts to SQL logins, then assign them to the role. 
Assign only authorized DBAs to the SQL Server System Administrators role. 


4.7 OS Guests access - Deny database login for the Guests OS group. Assuming your Guests group was not renamed as part of your OS lockdown: 
EXEC sp_denylogin 'Computer_Name\Guests' 


4.11 Fixed Server Roles Only use the fixed server roles sysadmin, serveradmin, 
setupadmin etc, to support DBA activity. 
Avoid assigning these roles to application database user accounts, application administrator accounts, application developer accounts or application roles. 

4.13 Statement Permissions Grant DDL statement permissions to only the database and schema owner, not individual users. 
DBO has all statement permissions for the database by default 

4.14 Database Owners Permissions - Ensure dbo owns all user-created database schemas Having dbo own all user-created database schemas prevents issues raised when users need to be deleted 

4.13 Stored Procedure Permissions - Grant execute permissions on stored procedures to database roles (not users). 
 
4.19 Using the GRANT option - Do not assign the GRANT option of object permission to a user or role. 
 
4.15 SQL Server Agent subsystem privileges - Restrict proxy access to required/approved subsystems Allowing access to CmdExec and ActiveX subsystems allows direct OS access and should be avoided unless business justifications for doing so exist. 
 
4.16 User-defined Database Roles - Create user-defined database roles to assign permissions to objects in the database when a pre-defined database role does not supply the appropriate permissions to a group of users. Not all organizations have a need for user-defined database roles. This may not apply to all organizations. 
 
4.17 Database Roles Avoid nesting database roles.

4.18 Users and Roles Ensure that the members of the roles (users/groups/other roles) in the target database actually exist. 

4.19 Application Roles Use application roles to limit access to data to users of specific applications. Use encryption to protect the role name and password in the connection string. Use “EXECUTE AS WITH 
NO REVERT” or “WITH COOKIE” to allow individuals to access the application without knowing the password. This provides a permission based rather than password based mechanism to sandbox access.. 

4.21 Linked or Remote Servers Use linked servers rather than remote servers where required. 
Disable linked servers otherwise Remote servers are available for backward compatibility purposes only. Applications that must execute stored procedures against remote instances of SQL Server should use 
linked servers instead. 

4.26 Linked or Remote Servers Configure linked or remote servers to use Windows authentication where required. Disable linked servers otherwise. 
When linking SQL Server databases, the user’s current identity will be used to authenticate the connection. 


4.27 Linked Server logins - Allow linked server access only to those logins that need it. Disable linked servers otherwise. 

4.28 Linked Server logins - Allow linked server access only to those logins that need it.

4.29 Ad Hoc Data Access - Disable ad hoc data access on all providers except SQL OLE DB, for all users except members of the sysadmin fixed role. Use network segmentation to prevent or limit desktop clients from making direct adhoc connections. Allow ad hoc data access only to trusted providers. Limit adhoc connections from MS Office applications (Excel, Access, Word, etc.). 


5.3 SQL Server Logs SQL Server audit data must be protected from loss. 
The SQL Server and SQL Server Agent logs must be backed up before they are overwritten. Adjust the number of logs to prevent data loss. 
The default is six. 

5.5 Profiler Events Capture the following events using SQL Profiler A third-party auditing tool may be used in lieu of SQL Profiler. (Use Idera SQL compliance manger)
Event Description of what the event records 


6.1 Backups – General Use Full database backups combined with differential or transaction log backups to restore the database to a specific point in time. Database backups should be made to another server or disk that is not physically attached to the same server as the database. This will reduce the risk of total loss in case of disk failure. 

6.2 System databases It is important to include the system databases in your backup plan i.e. the master, msdb and model databases. The tempdb database contains no permanent data and does not require backups. 

6.3 Backing up Master database - Backup the master database when any of the following events occur: 
•A database is created or deleted 
•Login accounts are created, deleted or 
modified 
•Server-wide or database settings are modified 

6.4 Backing up MSDB database - Backup the msdb database when any of the following events occur: 
•Alerts, jobs, schedules or operators are created, deleted or modified 
•Backups and restores are performed 
 
6.5 Backup Media Password - protect or encrypt the backup media. This ensures that the data is protected from unauthorized restores or from being accidentally overwritten. (Idera SQLsafe)
 
6.6 Limiting Network Activity To ensure backup files are protected, avoid performing activities such as backups and restores across the network. 
 
6.7 Access to Backup Files Restrict access to the backup files to System Administrators. 
 
6.8 Access to Backup Files Restrict restore permissions to DBAs and db_owners. 
 
6.9 Recommended periodic administrative procedures - Run the Microsoft Baseline Security Analyzer weekly and follow the security recommendations as closely as possible to secure the operating system. 

6.10 Recommended periodic administrative procedures Run the SQL Best Practices Analyzer regularly and note any changes to the environment. 

6.11 Enable Password Policy - Enforcement When a password change mechanism is introduced into clients and applications, enable password expiration. Always specify MUST_CHANGE when specifying a password on behalf of another principal. 

6.12 Periodic scan of Role Members - Periodically scan fixed server and database roles to ensure that only trusted individuals are members. 


7.1 SQL Server Agent service account - Configure replication agents to use a Windows account rather than a SQL Server Agent account. 
Grant only the required permissions to each agent. Use Windows Authentication for all replication agent connections. 
 
7.2 Replication administration roles - Avoid modifying replication administration permissions assigned to the roles by default. Only assign authorized application administrators and DBAs these roles. 
The permissions needed to support and administer replication are assigned to sysadmin, db_owner and replmonitor by default. 
 
7.3 Snapshot share folder Store the snapshot folder, which houses a snapshot of the replicated changes, on an explicit share and not an administrative share. 

7.4 Snapshot share folder permissions - Assign the following NTFS permissions: 
System and Administrators – FULL CONTROL, SQL Server Agent service account – READ and WRITE 
 
7.5 Publication Access List The domain accounts used by the SQL Server Agent service and the Replication proxy account must be entered in the Publication Access List so that all replication agents will be able to participate in the replication process. 
 
7.6 Secure Communications - Use secure connections, such as VPN or proxy servers, for all replication over the Internet. 
 
7.7 Database connections - Configure the database connections for replication agents to use Windows authenticated logons. 
 
7.8 Filtering - Employ replication filters to protect the data. 1 

7.9 Distribution databases - All distribution databases and snapshot files must be located in protected and audited locations. 
 

8.1 Ownership Chaining Use ownership chaining within a single database to simplify permissions management. 
Avoid using cross database ownership chaining. 

8.2 Role Assignments Assign permissions to roles rather than users. The principle of “Least Privilege” applies, thus users should not be given access to roles they do not need for their job function. 
Ensure that roles, rather than users own objects to avoid application changes when a user is dropped. 

8.3 Encrypted connections Enable encrypted connections between the user and the server. 
Consider allowing only encrypted connections. 
When allowing SQL Server authentication, encrypt either the network layer with IPSec or the session with SSL 

8.4 Error Handling Do not propagate errors back to the user. Log errors or transmit them to the system administrator. 

8.5 User Input Prevent SQL injection by validating all user input before transmitting it to the server. 
Only permit minimally privileged accounts to send user input to the server. Minimize the risk of SQL injection attack by using parameterized commands and stored procedures. 

8.6 Developer awareness Increase awareness of issues such as cross-site scripting, buffer overflows, SQL injection and dangerous APIs. 
8.7 Developer awareness Identify categories of threats that apply to your application, such as denial of service, escalation of privileges, spoofing, data tampering, information disclosure and repudiation. 

8.8 Security reviews Add security reviews to all stages of the application development lifecycle (from design to testing). 

</InterviewText>
  <PolicyMetrics>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>1</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 5.1</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is the nearest snapshot collection within an acceptable timeframe?
Recommendation: Prepare a schedule for reviewing audit information regularly.</ReportText>
      <Severity>2</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'30'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>2</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.2</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is the SQL Server version below the minimum acceptable level?
Recommendation: Ensure the Current SQL Server service pack and hotfixes are installed.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'8.00.2039'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>3</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.6, CIS 3.2.5</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is SQL Authentication enabled on the SQL Server? Recommendation: Select Windows authentication mode.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>4</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 3.2.6</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is Login Auditing enabled on the SQL Server? Recommendation: At a minimum, enable failed login attempts. Auditing of failed login attempts only is enabled by
default.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'Failure','All'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>5</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 3.2.4, CIS 8.1</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is Cross Database Ownership Chaining enabled on the SQL Server? Recommendation: Disable the cross_db_ownership_chaining option.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>6</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.9.1</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is Guest user access available on the SQL Server? Remove the guest user from all databases except msdb, master and tempdb.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'msdb','master','tempdb'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>7</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 4.7</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Do Suspect Logins exist on the SQL Server? Recommendation: Deny database login for the Guests OS group.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>8</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.10</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is C2 Audit Trace enabled on the SQL Server?
Recommendation: C2 Audit Mode– Set to 1 if no custom defined audit trace is enabled</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>9</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is a Proxy Account enabled on the SQL Server?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>10</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is DAC enabled remotely on the SQL Server? Recommendation: Disable the Dedicated Administrator Connection where not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>11</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Has anyone been granted permission to execute Integration Services stored procedures on the SQL Server? Recommendation: Disable the SSIS stored procedures or remove access if not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'sp_add_dtspackage','sp_enum_dtspackages','sp_add_job','sp_add_jobstep'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>13</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 3.8/CIS 9.8</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is SQL Mail or Database Mail enabled? Recommendation: Disable Database Mail where messaging is not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>14</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10, CIS 3.8, CIS 9.4</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is SQL Agent Mail enabled? Recommendation: Disable service if not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>15</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.7</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Do the SQL Server sample databases exist? Recommendation: Do not install the sample databases. Delete all sample databases if they already exist.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'Northwind','pubs','AdventureWorks','AdventureWorksDW'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>16</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey></ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Does "sa" account exist?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>17</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.8 (partial)/ CIS 4.9</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Does "sa" account have a blank password? Recommendation: Use a strong password for the "sa" login account.</ReportText>
      <Severity>3</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>18</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.9</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are System Table updates allowed?
Recommendation: Do not enable direct modifications to the system catalogs.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>19</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Does "Everyone" have view access to System Tables?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>20</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.12, CIS 3.6</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are startup stored procedures enabled? Recommendation: Disable scanning for startup </ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>21</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.12, CIS 3.6</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are any unexpected stored procedures marked to run at startup? Recommendation: Disable scanning for startup procedures</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
        <SeverityValues>'none'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
        <MetricId>22</MetricId>
        <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
        <ReportKey>CIS 3.10</ReportKey>
        <ReportText>
            Are any user stored procedures not encrypted? Ensure that all user-defined stored procedures are
            stored in encrypted format
        </ReportText>
        <Severity>1</Severity>
        <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
        <MetricId>23</MetricId>
        <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
        <ReportKey>CIS 3.11, CIS 3.12</ReportKey>
        <ReportText>
            Do user defined Extended Stored Procedures (XPs) exist? Recommendation: Avoid using user-defined extended stored procedures. If extended functionality is required, use Common Language Runtime (CLR) assemblies
            instead.
        </ReportText>
        <Severity>1</Severity>
        <SeverityValues>'none'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>24</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 3.13</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Do inappropriate permissions exist on dangerous Extended Stored Procedures (XPs)? Recommendation: Disable access to these extended stored procedures if their use is not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'xp_cmdshell','xp_available_media','xp_cmdshell','xp_dirtree','xp_dsninfo','xp_enumdsng','xp_enumerrorlogsg','xp_enumgroupsg','xp_eventlogg','xeddrivesg','xp_getfiledetailsg','xp_getnetnameg','xp_logeventg','xp_loginconfigg','xp_msverg','xp_readerrorlogg','xp_servicecontrol','xp_sprintfg','xp_sscanfg','xp_subdirsg','xp_unc_to_drive','xp_deletemailg','xtmsgg','xp_get_mapi_default_profileg','xp_get_mapi_profilesg','xp_readmailg','xp_sendmailg','xp_startmailg','xp_stopmail','xp_convertwebtaskg','xp_dropwebtaskg','xp_enumcodepagesg','xp_makewebtaskg','xp_readwebtaskg','xp_runwebtask','xp_snmp_getstateg','xp_snmp_raisetrap','sp_OACreateg','sp_OADestroyg','sp_OAGetErrorInfog','sp_OAGetPropertyg','sp_OAMethodg','sp_OASetProperty','sp_OAStop','xp_regaddmultistringg','xp_regdeletekeyg','xp_regdeletevalueg','xp_regenumvaluesg','xp_regremovemultistringg','xp_regwrite'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>25</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.11, CIS 3.2.7</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is Remote Access enabled? Recommendation: Remote Access– Set to 0 unless replication is being used or the requirement is justified</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>26</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 3.1</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are unexpected Protocols enabled? Recommendation: Disable the ‘Named Pipes’ network protocol.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'Shared Memory','TCP/IP'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>27</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 2.3</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are default TCP Ports used? Recommendation: Change SQL Server default ports from 1433 and 1434</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'1433','1434'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>28</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is SQL Server visible for browsing?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>29</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 4.15</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Can non sysadmins execute SQL Agent CmdExec jobs on the SQL Server? Recommendation: Restrict proxy access to required/approved subsystems</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>30</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10, CIS 3.5</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is replication Enabled on the SQL Server? Recommendation: Disable service if not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>31</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Do unexpected Registry Key Owners exist?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>32</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Do unexpected Registry Key Permissions exist?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>33</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.9.2</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are any SQL Server files on drives not using NTFS? Recomendatiion: Format all volumes with NTFS</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>34</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Do unexpected Executable File Owners exist?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>35</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Do unexpected Executable File Permissions exist?</ReportText>
      <Severity>2</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>36</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Do unexpected Database File Owners exist?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>37</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Does "Everyone" have access to database files?</ReportText>
      <Severity>3</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>38</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Do unexpected Database File Permissions exist?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>39</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is OS version at an acceptable level?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues>'Microsoft(R) Windows(R) Server 2003, Enterprise Edition, Service Pack 2','Microsoft(R) Windows(R) Server 2003 Enterprise x64 Edition, Service Pack 2','Microsoft(R) Windows(R) Server 2003, Standard Edition, Service Pack 2','Microsoft(R) Windows(R) Server 2003 Standard x64 Edition, Service Pack 2'</SeverityValues>
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>40</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is an unacceptable SQL Server Service Login Account used?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>41</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are Microsoft Reporting Services running?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>42</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are Analysis Services (OLAP) running? Recommendation: Disable service if not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>43</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is an unacceptable Analysis Service Login Account used?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>44</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are Notification Services running? Recommendation: Disable services that are not in use.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>45</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is an unacceptable Notification Service Login Account used?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>46</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are Integration Services running? Recommendation: Disable services that are not in use.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>47</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is an unacceptable Integration Service Login Account used?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>48</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is the SQL Server Agent running?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>49</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is an unacceptable SQL Server Agent Service Login Account used?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>50</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is Full-Text Search running?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>51</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is an unacceptable Full-Text Search Service Login Account used?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>52</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 1.10</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is the SQL Server Browser running? Recommendation: Disable service if not required.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>53</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is an unacceptable SQL Server Browser Service Login Account used?</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>54</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Are any servers in the policy missing audit data?</ReportText>
      <Severity>2</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>55</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is audit data incomplete?</ReportText>
      <Severity>2</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>56</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>false</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Is any audit data from non baseline snapshots?</ReportText>
      <Severity>2</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>57</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 4.9</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is the password policy enabled for all SQL Logins? Recommendation: Ensure that the SA account and all SQL Logins have strong passwords.</ReportText>
      <Severity>2</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>58</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey />
      <ReportText>Are any permissions granted to the public database role?</ReportText>
      <Severity>3</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>59</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 4.9</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Does any SQL Login have a blank password? Recommendation: Ensure that the SA account and all SQL Logins have strong passwords.</ReportText>
      <Severity>3</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>60</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 4.15</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Are any fixed roles assigned to the public role or guest user? Recommendation: Dp not grant object permissions to PUBLIC or GUEST.</ReportText>
      <Severity>1</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
    <PolicyMetric>
      <MetricId>61</MetricId>
      <IsEnabled>true</IsEnabled>
      <ReportKey>CIS 4.8</ReportKey>
      <ReportText>Is the BUILTIN/Administrators group assigned to the sysadmin role? Recommendation: Remove BUILTIN\Administraotrs SQL Login</ReportText>
      <Severity>2</Severity>
      <SeverityValues />
    </PolicyMetric>
  </PolicyMetrics>
</Policy>